<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!-- 
// 
// This is the place for your statements. The maximum 
// number of statements is theoretically unlimited, but
// less then 50 statements are advisable.
// If your are using German Umlauts and other special 
// characters, make sure, that you save this XML-file 
// as an UTF-8-document. White-space inbetween the 
// nodes are ignored. Any white-space within the text-
// nodes, including leading or trailing whitespace and 
// line breaks, is preserved.
//
// EXAMPLE
// Let's define some statements concerning FlashQ:
// Statement 1: FlashQ is very usefull.
// Statement 2: I prefer offline surveys.
// Statement 3: FlashQ is too complicated to configure.
//
// Each statement requires a seperate statement-node 
// consisting out of an opening and a closing tag. The 
// statement itself goes between this two tags. 
// The unique statement id is saved as an 
// attribute called 'id'. We have three exmaple 
// statements and we need therefore three statement-
// nodes and one parent-node. 
//
// <statements version="1.0" htmlparse="false">
//   <statement id="1">FlashQ is very usefull.</statement>
//   <statement id="2">I prefer offline surveys.</statement>
//   <statement id="3">FlashQ is too complicated to configure</statement>
// </statements>
// 
// ===================================================
// 
-->

<statements version="1.0" htmlParse="false">
  <statement id="1">Owning a car means thinking about costs like maintenance, insurance, parking and repair which become too much.</statement>
  <statement id="2">There are so many sharing car, bike and scooter options that I do not feel like I will need to own any vehicle.</statement>
  <statement id="3"> It is difficult to get groceries on a bike or walking so I would prefer a car.  </statement>
  <statement id="4"> I feel guilty taking a mode of transport that is not environmentally friendly but my time and money are more important.  </statement>
  <statement id="5"> Its easier to use public transport since I can find all the timings, the fastest and best possible route on my phone. </statement>
  <statement id="6"> I like travelling by bike because its faster, cheaper and gives a good start to the day. </statement>
  <statement id="7">If I had more money I would travel more. Now I try to travel less because it's expensive to travel.</statement>
  <statement id="8"> I've been online shopping a lot recently. This takes away the need for me to travel a lot.  </statement>
  <statement id="9"> The infrastructure to walk/bike/use Public transport is so good. I don’t think you ever need to use a car. </statement>
  <statement id="10">Public transport is expensive. It would be cheaper for me per ride if I had a car.</statement>
  <statement id="11"> 
I think its better using shared mobility than owning a vehicle as it is better for the environment. </statement>
  <statement id="12"> I only use a taxi when I can share the costs with someone. </statement>
  <statement id="13"> Owning a car is nice since you wouldn’t have to worry about getting a seat.  </statement>
  <statement id="14"> Owning a car can make it easier to travel.  </statement>
  <statement id="15"> I like the privacy a car gives when travelling. </statement>
  <statement id="16"> It is so difficult finding parking in cities which is why I would prefer using a taxi when I need a car. </statement>
  <statement id="17"> I don’t think we need a car anymore but my parents and other older members of my family still think its needed. </statement>
  <statement id="18">The environmental impact of a mode does matter, but I prefer my comfort.</statement>
  <statement id="19">I like using shared bikes and scooters. They're fast, cheap and I don’t worry about parking.</statement>
  <statement id="20">The weather is so unpredictable, its easier to travel if I own a car.</statement>
  <statement id="21"> Having a car can give an individual a sense of freedom. </statement>
  <statement id="22"> It is easy for me to use shared mobility. I can access it with my phone at any time and don’t need to worry about anything. </statement>
  <statement id="23"> Currently it is difficult for me to own a car/ regularly use a car since I cannot afford it. </statement>
  <statement id="24"> Even though the public transportation in the Netherlands is good. I think you still need a car sometimes. </statement>
  <statement id="25">Shared mobility is expensive so I prefer using public transport or just walking/biking.</statement>
  <statement id="26"> I think travelling via car since it gives a sense of safety. </statement>
  <statement id="27"> Using public transport is nice because you know exactly how much you will spend per ride. That is more difficult if you have a car.  </statement>
  <statement id="28"> Sometimes public transportation is unreliable because either the road is closed to there is some work in progress on a railway line. </statement>
  <statement id="29">Owning a car is too much of a hassle, especially if I'm living in a city. I rather spend that money elsewhere.</statement>
  <statement id="30"> I don’t want to use a car/ try to use the car less due to environmental reasons.  </statement>
  <statement id="31"> Using a car is more comfortable since you can stop anywhere you like and go on your own time.  </statement>
  <statement id="32">I don’t like using shared cars since you have to travel with someone you do not know. </statement>
  <statement id="33">  My need to travel has reduced in recent times since I can do everything online. </statement>
  <statement id="34"> If I were living away from a city I would prefer having a car for my commute.  </statement>
  <statement id="35">When I need to travel using public transport I have to plan a lot. I do not like doing that planning.</statement>
  <statement id="36">If there were more shared mobility options easily available I do not think I would need a car. </statement>
  <statement id="37"> The public transportation is so efficient that I do not feel the need to use a car. </statement>
  <statement id="38">Public transportation takes too long and I need to make multiple changes. So I would like using a car.</statement>
  <statement id="39"> I don’t want to use a car but I wouldn’t mind using once if its electric. </statement>
  <statement id="40"> I think its nice to live somewhere where all my needs are met at a walkable distance. This removes the need of having a car.  </statement>
</statements>